<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Frequently Asked Questions (FAQs) on Delta Operational Metrics Store (DeltaOMS)</title><link>https://databrickslabs.github.io/delta-oms/faq/</link><description>Recent content in Frequently Asked Questions (FAQs) on Delta Operational Metrics Store (DeltaOMS)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 14:50:11 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://databrickslabs.github.io/delta-oms/faq/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>General</title><link>https://databrickslabs.github.io/delta-oms/faq/general/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 14:50:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://databrickslabs.github.io/delta-oms/faq/general/</guid><description>Q. What is Delta Operational Metrics Store ?
Delta Operational metrics store (DeltaOMS) is a solution/framework for automated collection and tracking of Delta commit logs and other future operational metrics from Delta Lake, build a centralized repository for Delta Lake operational statistics and simplify analysis across the entire data lake.
The solution can be easily enabled and configured to start capturing the operational metrics into a centralized repository on the data lake.</description></item><item><title>Execution</title><link>https://databrickslabs.github.io/delta-oms/faq/execution/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 14:26:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://databrickslabs.github.io/delta-oms/faq/execution/</guid><description>Q. How do I get started ?
Please refer to the Getting Started guide
Q. How do I add databases to be monitored by DeltaOMS ?
You can add a database name to the DeltaOMS configuration table (by default called sourceconfig) using simple SQL INSERT statement.
Example:
INSERT INTO &amp;lt;omsDBName&amp;gt;.sourceconfig VALUES('&amp;lt;Database Name&amp;gt;',false, Map('wildCardLevel','0'))
For more details on the configurations and parameters, refer to Getting Started and Developer Guide
Q. What components will to be deployed for DeltaOMS ?</description></item><item><title>Security</title><link>https://databrickslabs.github.io/delta-oms/faq/security/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 14:26:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://databrickslabs.github.io/delta-oms/faq/security/</guid><description>Q. Would I need to give permissions to all my data for this solution to work ?
DeltaOMS processes the Delta transaction logs implementing the Delta protocol to capture the different operational metrics. These logs are stored under the folder _delta_log alongside your data files. DeltaOMS only requires access to this _delta_log folder for the tracked data locations.
For more details on how DeltaOMS works please refer to the Developer Guide</description></item></channel></rss>