<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Getting Started on Delta Operational Metrics Store (DeltaOMS)</title><link>https://databrickslabs.github.io/delta-oms/v0.5.0/getting_started/</link><description>Recent content in Getting Started on Delta Operational Metrics Store (DeltaOMS)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 14:50:11 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://databrickslabs.github.io/delta-oms/v0.5.0/getting_started/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pre-Requisites</title><link>https://databrickslabs.github.io/delta-oms/v0.5.0/getting_started/prerequisites/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 14:25:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://databrickslabs.github.io/delta-oms/v0.5.0/getting_started/prerequisites/</guid><description>Make sure you have the following available before proceeding :
Access to Databricks environment with access to Delta tables/databases Ability to create Databricks job and run them on new cluster Proper access permissions to create database, tables and write data to the desired OMS location Access to create libraries on your Databricks environment. Required to attach the relevant DeltaOMS (delta-oms) libraries (Optional) Able to access the DeltaOMS github repo for demo notebooks and scripts Databricks Runtime 11.</description></item><item><title>Setup</title><link>https://databrickslabs.github.io/delta-oms/v0.5.0/getting_started/setup/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 14:25:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://databrickslabs.github.io/delta-oms/v0.5.0/getting_started/setup/</guid><description>Initialize the DeltaOMS Database DeltaOMS can be configured through multiple methods :
Command line parameters - Limited to few configurations Spark configurations - All configurations.Refer to Additional Configurations section below for full details Command Line Parameters over-rides Spark Configurations.
For this tutorial we will use the command line parameters.More details about the other configurations can be found under Additional Configurations section.
Follow the below steps to initialize the DeltaOMS centralized Database and tables.</description></item><item><title>Execute</title><link>https://databrickslabs.github.io/delta-oms/v0.5.0/getting_started/execute/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 14:25:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://databrickslabs.github.io/delta-oms/v0.5.0/getting_started/execute/</guid><description>Execute the DeltaOMS Jobs You can run the jobs created in the above step to ingest and process the delta transaction information for the configured tables into the centralized DeltaOMS database.
For example, the OMSIngestion_* job(s) bring in the raw delta logs from the configured databases/tables and the OMSProcessing_* job processes the raw delta logs to format and enrich them for analytics.
For more advanced details on the working of these jobs please refer to the Developer Guide</description></item><item><title>Analyze</title><link>https://databrickslabs.github.io/delta-oms/v0.5.0/getting_started/analyze/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 14:25:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://databrickslabs.github.io/delta-oms/v0.5.0/getting_started/analyze/</guid><description>Run analytics using sample notebooks You can run some sample analytics on the data from the OMS database using the provided notebook
Modify the queries to reflect your configuration for OMS DB Name and other table names (if applicable).
Executing this notebook will give you an idea on the type of analysis and data structure that can be utilized as part of the DeltaOMS.
You can build on top of this notebook , customize this notebook to your liking and create your own Analytics insights and dashboards through Databricks notebooks and/or SQL Analytics.</description></item><item><title>Additional Configuration</title><link>https://databrickslabs.github.io/delta-oms/v0.5.0/getting_started/additionalconfigurations/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 14:25:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://databrickslabs.github.io/delta-oms/v0.5.0/getting_started/additionalconfigurations/</guid><description>Spark Configuration DeltaOMS uses multiple Spark configurations to control its different components.
DeltaOMS Spark configuration (spark.conf) details :
Configuration Key Description Required Example Default Value Applies to components databricks.labs.deltaoms.base.location Base location/path of the OMS Database on the Delta Lake Y dbfs:/spark-warehouse/oms.db, /tmp/spark-warehouse/oms.db None All databricks.labs.deltaoms.db.name OMS Database Name. This is the database where all the Delta log details will be collected Y oms.</description></item></channel></rss>