<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Developer Guide on Delta Operational Metrics Store (DeltaOMS)</title><link>https://databrickslabs.github.io/delta-oms/developer_guide/</link><description>Recent content in Developer Guide on Delta Operational Metrics Store (DeltaOMS)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 14:50:11 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://databrickslabs.github.io/delta-oms/developer_guide/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Configuration Tables</title><link>https://databrickslabs.github.io/delta-oms/developer_guide/configurationtables/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 14:27:39 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://databrickslabs.github.io/delta-oms/developer_guide/configurationtables/</guid><description>Source Config Default Name : sourceconfig
Table used for adding databases/paths/individual table to be tracked by DeltaOMS
Column Type Description path String Path to the Delta object to be tracked by DeltaOMS. Could be a database (all tables will be included), directory, individual table or specific path skipProcessing Boolean Flag to exclude processing a row parameters Map&amp;lt;String,String&amp;gt; Placeholder for dynamic parameters to be passed to DeltaOMS (supports easy future expansion).</description></item><item><title>Data Tables</title><link>https://databrickslabs.github.io/delta-oms/developer_guide/datatables/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 14:27:39 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://databrickslabs.github.io/delta-oms/developer_guide/datatables/</guid><description>Raw Actions Default Name : rawactions
Stores the raw actions captured through the ingestion of the _delta_log json files for all tracked tables. The schema has the columns matching the Actions from here(https://github.com/delta-io/delta/blob/master/core/src/main/scala/org/apache/spark/sql/delta/actions/actions.scala#L515) and the Delta Log Protocol with the following additional fields :
Column Type Description file_name String Name of the Delta log transaction json file. Eg. - dbfs:/user/hive/warehouse/sample.db/table1/_delta_log/00000000000000000025.json path String Path to the Delta table.</description></item><item><title>Data Model</title><link>https://databrickslabs.github.io/delta-oms/developer_guide/datamodels/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 14:27:39 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://databrickslabs.github.io/delta-oms/developer_guide/datamodels/</guid><description>DeltaOMS collects and processes the operational metrics provided by Databricks Delta operations
DeltaOMS centralizes and organizes the data according to the following Data Model.</description></item><item><title>Key Components</title><link>https://databrickslabs.github.io/delta-oms/developer_guide/components/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 14:27:39 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://databrickslabs.github.io/delta-oms/developer_guide/components/</guid><description>Initialization DeltaOMS provides the component com.databricks.labs.deltaoms.init.InitializeOMS for initializing
the centralized OMS database. The component creates the OMS DB at the location specified by the configuration settings. Note: This process will delete all existing data in the specified location.
Refer to Additional Configurations for full configuration settings.
Configuration Once DeltaOMS has been initialized, and the input sources configured Source Config, the component provided by com.databricks.labs.deltaoms.init.ConfigurePaths is executed to populate the internal path config tables.</description></item></channel></rss>